这绝对是被盗的太空巡洋舰极光号，舰长
It is definitely the stolen space cruiser, Captain, the Aurora.
我读到船上有六个人
I read six aboard.
呼叫频率
Hailing frequencies.
极光号，这是联邦星舰企业号，由詹姆斯·T·柯克舰长指挥
Aurora, this is the USS Enterprise, Captain James T. Kirk commanding.
[柯克]收到请回答
[Kirk] Acknowledge.
极光号，这里是企业号
Aurora, this is the Enterprise.
[柯克]你能听到我吗？
[Kirk] Do you read me ?
他们正在接收我们的信号，舰长
They are receiving us, Captain.
没有故障的迹象
I read no evidence of malfunction.
重复，联邦命令扣押你们…
Repeat, Federation orders to detain you for...
[苏鲁]他们正在转向，长官
[SULU] They're veering off, sir.
改变航线，追赶并超越
Change course. Pursue and overtake.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
牵引波束待命
Stand by tractor beams.
待命中，长官
Standing by, sir.
如果它继续前进，它将进入罗慕伦空间
If it continues on course, it will enter Romulan space.
发射
Engage.
牵引波束已接合
Tractor beam engaged.
带他们进来
Bring them in.
@
↪
他们想逃跑
They're struggling to escape.
他们的引擎严重过热，舰长
Their engines are seriously overheating, Captain.
极光号，切断动力，你让你的船超载了
Aurora, cut power. You are overtaxing your ship.
动力逼近临界
Power approaching critical.
他们不能继续走了
They cannot continue.
应急动力接入牵引波束
Emergency power to tractor beams.
舰桥呼叫传送室，斯科提，你准备好传送了吗？
Bridge to Transporter Room. Scotty, are you ready to transport?
是的，舰长
Aye, Captain.
动力超过临界
Power beyond critical.
快要爆炸了
Explosion is imminent.
我们在传送范围内吗？
Are we within transportation range?
还没有，长官
Not yet, sir.
极光号人员，准备好传送上船
Aurora personnel, stand by to be transported aboard.
启动
Energize.
他们在船上吗？
Are they aboard?
斯科提，他们在船上吗？
Scotty, are they aboard?
是的，舰长
Aye, Captain.
他们在船上，而且有很多
They are. And a nice lot, too.
[柯克]宇宙，最后的边疆
[KIRK] Space, the final frontier.
这些是星舰企业号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务：探索未知的新世界
Its five year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
寻找新生命和新文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇踏前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
星际旅行：原初
第三季第二十集
通往伊甸之路
The Way to Eden
[柯克]舰长日志，星历5832.3
[Kirk] Captain's log, stardate 5832.3.
卡图兰大使的儿子是我们从被盗的巡洋舰极光号上
The son of the Catuallan ambassador is one of six
传送过来的六个人之一
we have beamed aboard from the stolen cruiser Aurora.
我们奉命非常周到地对待他
We have been ordered to handle him with extreme delicacy,
因为的联邦和卡图兰之间
because the treaty negotiations now in progress
正在进行的条约谈判正处于关键阶段
between the Federation and Catualla are in a crucial phase.
斯科提，带他们去简报室
Scotty, take them to the briefing room.
女人[通过对讲机]我们没心情，赫伯特
WOMAN [OVER INTERCOM] We are not in the mood, Herbert.
伊琳娜？
Irina?
[所有人对话]
[ALL TALK]
谢谢
Thank you.
男人[通过对讲机]告诉赫伯特不行
MAN [OVER INTERCOM] Tell Herbert it's no go.
怎么了？
What's going on?
[斯科提]他们拒绝，长官
[SCOTTY] They refuse.
为什么？
Why?
我不知道
I don't know.
他们大部分人只是坐在地上
They're just sitting on the floor, the lot of them.
你可以听到他们，我要派警卫过来吗？
You can hear them yourself. Shall I send for security?
不，我马上下来
No. I'll be right down.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
歌声：不行，不行，不行…
CHANTS: No go, no go, no go...
你们中的哪一个是汤戈·拉德？
Which one of you is Tongo Rad?
你没有被捕要感谢你父亲的影响
You can thank your father's influence that you're not under arrest.
除了劫机，你还面临违反飞行规定
In addition to piracy, you've left yourself open to charges of violating flight regulations,
进入敌对空间并危及他人及自身生命的指控
entering hostile space and endangering the lives of others as well as your own.
我在流血
I'm bleeding.
此外，你还造成了星际事件
In addition, you've caused an interstellar incident
这可能已经摧毁了你们星球和联邦之间谈判的一切
which may have destroyed everything that's been negotiated between your planet and the Federation.
你真是伶牙俐齿，赫伯特
You've got a hard lip, Herbert.
如果你有解释，我洗耳恭听
If you have an explanation, I am prepared to hear it.
史波克先生，把他们带到医务室进行医疗检查
Mr. Spock, take them to Sickbay for a medical check.
爆炸可能有辐射
There may have been radiation from the explosion.
舰长，你要是允许的话
Captain, with your permission...
当然可以
By all means.
一
One.
我们是一
We are One.
一是开始
One is the beginning.
你是一吗，赫伯特？
Are you One, Herbert?
我不是赫伯特
I am not Herbert.
他不是赫伯特，我们引起了他的注意
He's not Herbert. We reach.
如果你说出你们的目的和目标
If you will state your purpose and your objectives,
也许我们可以达成共识
perhaps we can arrive at a mutual understanding.
如果你了解一，你就知道我们的目的
If you understand One, you know our purpose.
我更想听到你说出来
I would prefer that you state it.
我们背弃混乱，寻找开始
We turn our backs on confusion and seek the beginning.
你的目的地是哪里？
What is your destination?
伊甸星球
The planet Eden.
那个星球是个神话
That planet is a myth.
我们抗议在违背我们意愿的情况下
And we protest against being harassed,
被骚扰、追捕、攻击、扣押和运送到这里。
pursued, attacked, seized and transported here against our wishes.
是的，兄弟
Right, brother.
我们不承认联邦法规
We do not recognize Federation regulations
也不承认战争行为
nor the existence of hostilities.
我们不承认任何权威，除了我们自己
We recognize no authority, save that within ourselves.
嗯，不管你是否承认权威，在这艘船上我就是权威
Well, whether you recognize authority or not, I am it on this ship.
我奉命和平地将你们送回星际基地
I'm under orders to transport you back to Starbase peaceably.
从那里你们将被运送到各自的星球
From there you'll be ferried to your various planets.
因为我的命令，你们不是囚犯，而是客人
Because of my orders, you are not prisoners, but guests.
我希望你们表现地像个客人
I expect you to behave as such.
哦，赫伯特，你太呆板了
Oh, Herbert, you are stiff.
史波克先生，你似乎了解这些人，你来招待他们
Mr. Spock, you seem to understand these people. You will deal with them.
我们恭敬地请求你带我们去伊甸
We respectfully request that you take us to Eden.
医务室的事务结束后
And after they are finished in sick bay,
确保他们被护送回各自的住处，满足他们的一切要求
see to it that they're escorted back to their proper quarters and given whatever care they need.
[史波克]是的，舰长
[Spock] Yes, Captain.
我们恭敬地请求你带我们去伊甸
We respectfully request that you take us to Eden.
我收到的命令正相反
I have orders to the contrary.
这不是一艘客船
This is not a passenger ship.
[全体一起唱]赫伯特！赫伯特！赫伯特！
[ALL CHANT] Herbert! Herbert! Herbert!
帕尔默上尉，通知星际基地
Lieutenant Palmer, notify Star base.
我们捉到了偷太空巡洋舰极光号的六个人
We have the six aboard who stole the space cruiser Aurora.
遗憾的是，太空巡洋舰被摧毁了
Regrettably, the space cruiser itself was destroyed.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
给卡图兰大使的私人信息，他的儿子很安全
Personal note to the Catullan ambassador: His son is safe.
舰长
Captain.
怎么了？
Yes, what is it?
长官，我觉得我认识其中一个人
Sir, I believe I know one of them.
我想我至少认得她的声音
At least, I think I recognize her voice.
她的名字是伊琳娜·加柳林
Her name is Irina Galliulin.
我们曾一起在星际舰队学院学习
We were in Starfleet Academy together.
他们中有人原来是学院的？
One of those was in the Academy?
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
她…退学了
She... dropped out.
她…
She...
你想见她吗？
Do you wish to see her?
允许离开你的职位
Permission to leave your post.
谢谢，长官
Thank you, sir.
他们在病房吗？
Are they in the Sickbay?
是的，舰长
Yes, Captain.
史波克先生…他们真的相信伊甸的存在吗？
Mr. Spock... do they really believe that Eden exists?
许多神话都是基于真理的，舰长，它们并非无知
Many myths are based on truth, Captain, and they are not unintelligent.
他们的领袖塞夫林博士，他是…
Their leader, Dr. Sevrin, is a man...
塞夫林博士是他们的领袖？
Dr. Sevrin is their leader ?
是的，迪布隆星上的一位杰出的研究工程师
Yes. A brilliant research engineer in the fields of acoustics,
专攻声学、通讯和电子领域
communications and electronics on Tiburon.
当他发起这项运动时，他被免职
He was dismissed from his post when he started this movement.
汤戈·拉德继承了父亲在空间研究领域的才能
Tong Rad inherits his father's extraordinary abilities in the field of space studies.
但是他们拒绝了这些技术及其带来的一切
But they've rejected all that and all that this technology provides.
他们寻求本原
And they seek the primitive.
有很多人对我们创造的东西感到不舒服
There are many who are uncomfortable with what we have created.
这几乎是一种生物反抗
It is almost a biological rebellion.
一种对计划好的社区
A profound revulsion against the planned communities,
设计好的，无菌的，巧妙平衡的大气的方案
the programming, the sterilized, artfully balanced atmospheres.
他们渴望春天来临的伊甸
They hunger for an Eden where spring comes.
所有人都渴望，这深深地印在在我们记忆深处
All do. The cave is deep in our memory.
是的，没错，舰长
Yes, that is true, Captain.
但我们不会偷太空巡洋舰，也不会像不负责任的孩子一样行事
But we don't steal space cruisers and act like irresponsible children.
是什么让你对他们如此同情？
What makes you so sympathetic toward them?
与其说是同情，不如说是好奇，舰长
It is not sympathy, so much as curiosity, Captain.
想了解的愿望
A wish to understand.
他们认为自己与他们的世界格格不入
They regard themselves as aliens in their own worlds,
这样的处境我有点熟悉
a condition with which I am somewhat familiar.
史波克
Spock.
赫伯特是什么意思？
What does Herbert mean?
这个词有点不中听，舰长
It is somewhat uncomplimentary, Captain.
赫伯特是个小官
Herbert was a minor official
因其僵化和有限的思维模式而臭名昭著
notorious for his rigid and limited patterns of thought.
好吧，我会尽量不那么死板地思考
Well, I shall try to be less rigid in my thinking.
♪寻找美好的土地♪
♪ Looking for the good land ♪
♪误入迷途♪
♪ Going astray ♪
♪别哭，别哭♪
♪ Don't cry, don't cry ♪
♪哦，我不能吃蜂蜜♪
♪ Oh, I can't have honey ♪
♪我不能吃奶油♪
♪ And I can't have cream ♪
♪要活着，不要死♪
♪ Gonna live, not die ♪
♪有一天，站在这一切的中间♪
♪ Stand in the middle of it all one day ♪
♪我看着它在我周围闪闪发光并说♪
♪ I look at it shining all around me and say ♪
♪我在这里♪
♪ I'm here ♪
♪在美好的土地上♪
♪ In the good land ♪
♪在新大陆♪
♪ In the new land ♪
♪我在这里♪
♪ I'm here ♪
打扰一下，伊琳娜·加柳林和你们在一起吗？
Excuse me. Is Irina Galliulin with you?
她正在体检
She's getting her physical.
要打着响指雀跃
Gonna crack my knuckles and jump for joy,
我从麦考伊医生那里得到了一份健康证明
I got a clean bill of health from Dr. McCoy.
哈哈哈
Ha ha ha.
你认识伊琳娜？
You know Irina?
告诉我，你为什么穿那么些衣服？
Tell me, why do you wear all those clothes?
你怎么呼吸？
How do you breathe?
[叹气]
[Sighs]
你下一个
You're next.
伊琳娜…
Irina...
帕维尔·安德烈维奇
Pavel Andreievich.
我想过我们可能会相遇
I had thought we might encounter each other.
你知道我在企业号上吗？
You knew I was on the Enterprise?
我听说过
I had heard.
伊琳娜，为什么…
Irina, why...
来
Come.
你怎么能这样对自己？
How could you do this to yourself?
你本是个科学家，现在看看你
You were a scientist. And now look at you.
看看你自己，帕维尔
Look at yourself, Pavel.
你为什么要那么做？
Why did you do it?
你又是为什么？
Why did you?
我为自己感到自豪
I'm proud of what I am.
我相信我所做的
I believe in what I do.
你能这么说吗？
Can you say that?
是的
Yes.
我们不应该这样针锋相对，帕维尔
We should not tear at each other so, Pavel.
我们应该在欢乐中重逢
We should meet again in joy.
今天，当我第一次知道跟着我们的是你的船时，我想起了你…
Today when I first knew it was your ship that followed us, I thought of you...
并想知道我会发现什么
and wondered what I would find.
我回忆起了很多
And I remembered so much.
尽管穿着那件制服，我看到的还是以前认识的那个帕维尔
In spite of that uniform, I still see the same Pavel I used to know.
你对你所做的事情感到快乐吗？
Are you happy in what you do?
是的
Yes.
那么我接受你的所作所为
Then I accept what you do.
你甚至像他们一样说话
You even talk like them.
你为什么离开？
Why did you go away?
离开的是你
It was you who went.
我回去找你了
I came back to look for you.
我找过了
I looked.
你去哪儿了？
Where did you go?
我留在了城市，和朋友们
I stayed in the city. With friends.
你从来没有感同身受过，从没
You never felt as I did. Never.
我当然有
I did.
你没有感觉到那么多
You don't have it in you to feel so much.
即使我们很亲近，你内心也没有和我在一起
Even when we were close, you weren't with me.
你在神游，在想别的事情
You were off, thinking of something else.
你为什么躲着我？
Why did you stay away?
因为你不赞成我
Because you disapproved of me.
就像你现在一样
Just as you do now.
哦，帕维尔，你一直都是这样
Oh, Pavel, you have always been like this.
那么正确，而内心，充满挣扎
So correct. And inside, the struggle not to be.
听从你的内心，你会更快乐，你会明白的
Give in to yourself. You will be happier. You'll see.
去找你的朋友
Go to your friends.
[人群大喊]
[PEOPLE SHOUTING]
释放塞夫林博士！释放塞夫林博士！
Free Dr. Sevrin !Free Dr. Sevrin !
我们想马上见他！
We want to see him right now!
但我们现在想见他！
But we want to see him now!
一起唱：赫伯特！赫伯特！赫伯特！
ALL CHANT: Herbert! Herbert! Herbert!
我以为所有动物都被关在笼子里
I thought all the animals were kept in cages.
怎么了，老骨头？
What's going on, Bones?
麻烦，这位朋友不想做检查
Trouble. Friend here didn't want a checkup.
原来是有原因的
Turns out there's a reason.
我不接受你的发现
I refuse to accept your findings.
你没有选择
You don't have the choice.
它们是偏见的产物，不是科学
They are the product of prejudice, not science.
我不知道这个人打算在一个原始星球上做什么
I don't know what this man was planning on doing on a primitive planet,
但假设有这么一个星球存在
but assuming one did exist,
我可以告诉你，如果他在那里定居，会发生什么
I can tell you what would have happened had he settled there.
毫无根据
Untrue.
原住民活下来的人手甚至不够去埋死人
Wouldn't have been enough of those primitives left to bury their dead.
都是想象，臆测
Fantasy. Fantasy.
我倒希望是
I wish it were.
一个讨厌的小虫子在过去几年进化了，吉姆
A nasty little bug evolved in the last few years, Jim.
我们洁净，无菌的文明产生了它
Our aseptic, sterilized civilizations produced it.
新合成球菌，这是致命的
Synthococcus novae. It's deadly.
我们能对它免疫，但我们还没有学会应对它的所有问题
We can immunize against it, but haven't learned to lick all the problems yet.
他有吗？其他人呢？
Does he have it? And the others?
其他人很干净，他没有感染，他是一个携带者
Well, the others are clear. He doesn't have it. He's a carrier.
还记得你的古代历史，伤寒玛丽吗？
Remember your ancient history? Typhoid Mary?
他对它免疫，就像她一样
He's immune to it, as she was,
但他携带疾病并传播给其他人
but he carries the disease and spreads to others.
船员有危险吗？
Is the crew in danger?
我不知道
I don't know.
他们都进行了全谱免疫接种
They all had full spectrum immunizations before boarding.
我猜是他的朋友们也接种过
My guess is his friends have had shots too.
但定期的加强注射是必要的
But a regular program of booster shots is necessary.
我得检查船上的每个人，可能会有遗漏
I'll have to check everyone on the ship, there could be some skips.
同时，他应该被完全隔离
In the meantime, he should be placed in total isolation.
这太离谱了
This is outrageous.
你不是在隔离我，而是在囚禁我
You're not isolating me. You're imprisoning me.
你捏造了罪名，认定我有罪，判我刑！
You invent a crime, find me guilty and sentence me!
你想自己进行测试吗，博士？
Would you like to run the test yourself, Doctor?
你上船前就知道你是一个携带者，不是吗？
You knew you were a carrier before you came aboard, didn't you?
不！
No!
那你为什么拒绝检查？
Then why did you fight the examination?
它侵犯了我的权利
It was an infringement on my rights!
把他隔离起来
Put him in isolation.
准备接受反对意见，吉姆，他们有一大帮人
Be ready for the objections, Jim. They are a vocal lot.
是的，我准备好了
Yes, I'm ready.
柯克呼叫警卫
Kirk to security.
我想要一个看守塞夫林博士，直到另行通知
I want a guard maintained on Dr. Sevrin until further notice.
老骨头，我们还要多久才能知道船员是否受到这种感染的威胁？
Bones, how long before we know whether the crew's been endangered by this infection?
它会在24小时内显示，这是一种致命的菌株
It'll show in 24 hours. It's a virulent strain.
你和他们不是一起的
You don't belong with them.
你知道我们想要什么
You know what we want.
你也想要，来，加入我们
You want it, too. Come, join us.
你怎么知道我想要什么？
How do you know what I want?
你很年轻
You're young.
想想年轻吧，兄弟
Think young, brother.
你让它很诱人
You make it tempting.
苏鲁先生
Mr. Sulu.
苏鲁先生，解释一下
Mr. Sulu, explain.
没有解释，长官
No explanation, sir.
我们会释放塞夫林博士，只要我们认为他在医学上是安全的
Dr. Sevrin will be released when we think he is medically safe.
♪死板的人把我的心灵关进监狱♪
♪ Stiff man putting my mind in jail ♪
♪法官敲响木槌说：“不得保释”♪
♪ And the judge bangs the gavel and say, "No bail" ♪
♪舔他的手并摇我的尾巴♪
♪ Gonna lick his hand and wag my tail ♪
赫伯特！
Herbert!
斯科提[通过对讲机]轮机部呼叫舰桥
SCOTTY [OVER INTERCOM] Engineering to bridge.
是的，斯科提，怎么了？
Yes, Scotty, what is it?
我把一个你称之为打赤脚的人从这里赶了出去
Captain, I just had to give one of those barefooted what do you call 'ems the boot out of here.
她大摇大摆地走进来，试图煽动我的船员不满
She came in bold as brass, tried to incite my crew to disaffect.
谢谢，斯科提
Thank you, Scotty.
史波克先生，我似乎无法与这些人沟通
Mr. Spock, I don't seem to be able to communicate with these people.
你认为你能说服他们规矩点吗？
Do you think you can persuade them to behave?
我会尝试的，舰长
I shall make an attempt, Captain.
谢谢，史波克先生
Thank you, Mr Spock.
要不是那个大使的儿子
If it weren't for that ambassador's son,
他们都会在禁闭室里
they'd all be in the brig.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
[柯克]舰长日志，星历5832.5
[KIRK] Captain's log, stardate 5832.5.
塞夫林博士追随者的傲慢正在企业号上造成无法忍受的局面
The arrogance of Dr. Sevrin and his followers is creating an intolerable situation aboard the Enterprise.
如果持续下去，我将被迫使用控制装置
If it continues, I'll be forced to use controls
那可能有悖于星际舰队的建议
which might not agree with Starfleet's suggestion
即以极端宽容的态度处理它们
that they be handled with extreme tolerance.
他们的行为不是我指使的
I have no influence over what they do.
他们尊重你，他们会听你的理由
They respect you. They will listen to your reasoning.
为他们起见，你必须阻止他们
For their sake, you must stop them.
塞夫林博士，我有能力帮助你和你的团队
Dr. Sevrin, I am in a position to help you and your group.
我可以使用企业号的资源
I can use the resources of the Enterprise
确定伊甸是否真的存在
to determine whether or not Eden actually exists
并绘制其确切位置
and to plot its exact location.
我可以向联邦提出申请，允许你们团队在该星球上进行殖民
I can present a case to Federation to allow your group to colonize that planet.
你和你的人目前都没有被指控犯罪
Neither you nor your people are at present charged with a crime.
然而，煽动不满是犯罪行为
However, incitement to disaffection is criminal.
联邦绝不允许犯罪分子对一个星球进行殖民
The Federation will never allow the colonization of a planet by criminals.
如果他们一直这样，他们将被指控并永远被禁止进入伊甸
If they persist, they will be so charged and for ever barred from Eden.
像我一样被禁止
As I have been barred.
那你知道你是一个携带者
Then you knew you were a carrier.
我当然知道
Of course I knew.
你已经调查了我的生活
You've researched my life.
你读过限制我只能在先进技术地区出行的命令
You've read the orders restricting me to travel only in areas of advanced technology
因为我携带的东西
because of what my body carries.
我不明白的是你为什么不服从这些命令
What I fail to understand is why you disobey those orders.
因为这对我来说是毒药！
Because this is poison to me!
这…你呼吸的东西，你生活的东西
This... stuff you breath, this stuff you live in.
我们在每个星球上铺设的人工大气防护罩
Shields of artificial atmosphere that we have layered about every planet.
那些为你们运行飞船和生活的电脑程序
The programs in those computers that run your ship and your lives for you,
它们培养了我身体携带的东西
they bred what my body carries.
这就是你的科学对我所做的
That's what your science has done to me.
你已经感染了我
You've infected me.
只有原始可以净化我
Only the primitives can cleanse me.
在我加入他们之前，我无法净化自己
I cannot purge myself until I am among them.
只有他们的生活方式是正确的，我必须去找他们
Only their way of living is right. I must go to them.
你的存在会摧毁你寻找的人
Your very presence will destroy the people you seek.
你肯定知道的
Surely you know that.
我要到他们那里去，与他们合而为一
I shall go to them and be One with them.
我们将一起建立一个银河系从未见过的世界
And together we shall build a world such as this galaxy has never seen.
一个世界，一种生活
A world. A life.
一种生活
A life.
现在你要试着说服我
So now you're gonna try to persuade me
你的技术会为我找到治疗方法
that your technologies will find a cure for me,
然后我就可以走了
and then I'll be free to go.
是的，博士
Yes, Doctor.
因此，我应该说服我的朋友们守规矩，
And for that reason I should persuade my friends to behave
这样他们也将被允许进入伊甸
so that they, too, will be allowed.
是的，博士
Yes, Doctor.
好的，你让他们进来，我会和他们谈谈
All right. You send them in. I'll talk to them.
塞夫林博士疯了
Dr. Sevrin is insane.
我还没咨询过麦考伊医生，但我对此毫不怀疑
I have not consulted Dr. McCoy, but I have no doubt of it.
我会让老骨头检查他
I'll have Bones check him out.
史波克，抱歉，你对他非常尊重
Spock, I'm sorry. You had great respect for him.
但它确实解释了他们做了什么
But it does explain some of what they've done.
他的病情不影响我对运动的兴趣
His condition does not affect my interest in the movement.
他们寻求的东西并不疯狂
There is no insanity in what they seek.
我做出了一个承诺，我想遵守
I made a promise which I should like to keep.
要是你允许，我必须找到伊甸
With your permission, I must locate Eden.
我将在我的宿舍工作
I shall work in my quarters.
我可以在辅助控制上得到契科夫先生的帮助吗？
May I have the assistance of Mr. Chekov in auxiliary control?
当然
Certainly.
契科夫先生，协助史波克先生
Mr. Chekov, assist Mr. Spock.
舰桥呼叫医务室，我是麦考伊
Bridge to Sickbay.  McCoy here.
老骨头
Bones,
什么事，舰长
Yes, Captain.
我想和你谈谈
I'd like to talk to you.
[柯克]舰长日志，星历5832.6
[KIRK] Captain's log, stardate 5832.6.
我已要求麦考伊医生查看星舰医疗记录
I have asked Dr. McCoy to check Starfleet medical records
验证史波克先生的怀疑，塞夫林博士疯了
to verify Mr. Spock's suspicion that Dr. Sevrin is insane.
尽管塞夫林博士很反感我们，他还是答应了史波克先生
In spite of Dr. Sevrin 's antipathy to us, he has promised Mr. Spock
他的追随者会遵守我们的规则
that he will order his disciples to conform to our rules and regulations.
[门声]
[DOOR BUZZES]
进来
Come in.
我打扰你了吗？
Am I crossing you?
没有
No.
我只是在想…
I was just thinking...
嘿，兄弟，你玩吗？
Hey, brother, do you play?
是瓦肯人的吗？
Is it Vulcan?
我可以试试吗？
Can I try it?
@嗬嗬，就是现在
Ho ho, that's now!
现在是真的了
That's real now.
我明白了，兄弟，我真的明白了
I reach that, brother. I really do.
给
Give.
嘿，你和我们来一场演奏会怎么样？会很棒的
Hey, how about a session, you and us? It would sound.
这就是我来的目的，我说
That's what I came for. I wanted to ask,
我本来想问楼上的大白舰长的，但他不理解我们
you know, great white captain upstairs, but he don't reach us.
但，呃，他会同意开演奏会吗？我是说
But, uh, would he shake on a session? I mean,
我们想合作，就像你要求的那样，所以我问问
We want to cooperate, like you ask, so I'm asking.
如果我理解正确
If I understand you correctly,
我相信答案可能是肯定的
I believe the answer might be yes.
我去传话
I'll spread the word.
我可以进去吗？
Am I allowed in?
是的
Yes.
我一直在找你，帕维尔
I have been looking for you, Pavel.
这是什么房间？
What room is this?
辅助控制室
Auxiliary control.
干什么的？
What's it for?
如果主控制室故障或损坏
Should the main control room break down or suffer damage,
我们可以在这里操控这艘船
we can navigate the ship from here.
你想干什么？
What do you want?
道歉，我不应该取笑你的，那太伤人了
To apologize. I should not have teased you. It was cruel.
没关系
It does not matter.
哦，有关系
Oh, but it does.
它违背了我所相信的一切
It is against everything I believe in.
让我们不要讨论你的信仰
Let us not discuss your beliefs.
而且我不喜欢你生我的气
And I do not like having you angry with me,
或者不赞成我
or disapproving.
那你为什么要做这样的事情？
Then why do you do such things?
你在做什么？
What are you working on?
我正在协助史波克先生找到你的伊甸
I am assisting Mr. Spock in locating your Eden.
哦，现在是你在取笑我
Oh, now you are teasing me.
我没有
I am not.
这些磁带包含星图
These tapes contain star charts
我们在这里投影不同行星的轨道
and we project the orbits of the various planets here.
呃，通过数学过程，我们确定
Uh, by mathematical process, we determine
它们是否受到尚未绘制的其他天体的影响
whether or not they are affected by other bodies not yet charted.
你知道所有这些东西？
Do you know all these things?
要是有不知道的就去电脑库里查
What I do not know I find out from the computer banks.
如果…我什么都不知道
If... I knew nothing at all,
我可以通过学习储存在那里面的东西来操纵这艘飞船
I could navigate the ship simply by studying what is stored in there.
它们包含了所有人类知识的总和
They contain the sum of all human knowledge.
它们解决我们在导航
They solve our problems of navigation.
控制
of control,
生命支持方面的问题
of life support.
它们告诉你们该做什么，你们就按照它们的吩咐去做
They tell you what to do and you do what they tell you.
不，我们也用自己的判断
No. We use our own judgment also.
我永远无法听从电脑
I could never obey a computer.
你永远不听任何人的话
You could never listen to anyone.
你总是必须与众不同
You always had to be different.
不一样，是我想成为的
Not different. What I wanted to be.
做你想做的事并没有错
There is nothing wrong in doing what you want.
[通讯器发出哔哔声]
[COMMUNICATOR BLEEPS]
史波克[通过对讲机]：我没有收到，契科夫先生
SPOCK [OVER INTERCOM] : I am not receiving, Mr. Chekov.
史波克呼叫契科夫，重复，我没有收到
Spock to Chekov. Repeat. I am not receiving.
对不起，史波克先生
I am sorry, Mr. Spock.
我被一时耽搁了
I was momentarily delayed.
他叫苏鲁，武器和导航专家
His name is Sulu, specialist in weapons and navigation.
他的爱好是植物学
His hobby is botany.
可能吗？
Can?
可能，我懂植物学，它是我最喜欢的研究
Can. I reach botany. It's my favorite of studies.
你的呢？
What's yours?
瓦肯人
Vulcan.
史波克现在几乎是一了
Spock is practically One now.
所有东西都可以通过辅助控制进行处理
Everything can be handled from auxiliary control.
计算机包含我们需要的所有信息
The computers contain all the information we need.
我们能做到
We can do it.
演出即将开始！
It starts to chime!
什么时候？
When will it?
很快，就像他说的，现在
Soonest. Like he said, now.
我们应该都出去尽可能地热热场
We should all go out and try to swing as many as possible over.
你有什么特别的方法让他们摇摆起来吗？
You suggest any special ways to swing them?
只要友好一点
Just be friendly.
你知道如何友好相处
You know how to be friendly.
那么他们就会很友好
Then they'll be friendly.
♪我在谈论你♪
♪ I'm talking 'bout you ♪
♪我在谈论我♪
♪ I'm talking about me ♪
♪遥远的过去星系是新的♪
♪ Long time back when the galaxy was new ♪
♪人知道他得做些什么♪
♪ Man found out what he had to do ♪
♪发现他必须吃，他发现他必须喝♪
♪ Found he had to eat and he found he had to drink ♪
♪很久之后，他发现他必须思考♪
♪ And a long time later, he found he had to think ♪
♪是的，思考♪
♪ Yes, think ♪
我站在这里想知道   什么？
I'm standing here wondering.  What?
♪如果一个人告诉另一个人，“别挡道”♪
♪ If a man tells another man, "Out of my way" ♪
♪他一整天都在给自己惹事♪
♪ He piles up trouble for himself all day ♪
♪但各种麻烦都过去了♪
♪ But all kinds of trouble come to an end ♪
♪当一个人对另一个人说“做我的朋友”♪
♪ When a man tells another man, "Be my friend" ♪
♪我的朋友♪
♪ My friend ♪
会是什么呢？
Well, what's it going to be?
♪有一英里宽的鸿沟♪
♪ There's a mile wide emptiness ♪
♪在你我之间♪
♪ Between you and me ♪
♪无法跨越它♪
♪ Can't reach across it ♪
♪几乎看不到♪
♪ Hardly even see ♪
♪有人应该以一种方式迈出一步♪
♪ Someone ought to take a step one way or other ♪
♪让我们说再见或让我们说兄弟♪
♪ Let's say goodbye or let's say brother ♪
♪兄弟♪
♪ Brother ♪
♪嘿，那里的人♪
♪ Hey, out there ♪
♪我看见你了♪
♪ I see you ♪
♪让我们聚在一起找点乐子♪
♪ Let's get together and have some fun ♪
♪我不知道该怎么做，但必须要做♪
♪ I don't know how to do it, but it's got to be done ♪
[忧郁的伴奏]
[BLUES VAMP]
至少我们知道他们在哪里，他们在做什么
At least we know where they are and what they're doing.
我不知道为什么年轻人都是没规没矩的
I don't know why a young mind has to be undisciplined one.
他们是麻烦精
They're troublemakers!
我在那个年纪时经常遇到小麻烦，斯科提，你呢？
I used to get into little trouble when I was that age, Scotty, didn't you?
舰长，我没有收到控制器的响应
Captain, I get no response on controls.
我们正在偏离航线
We're going off course.
短路了
It's shorted.
不，它被接到了什么地方
No, it's channeled over somewhere.
呼叫辅助控制
To auxiliary control.
舰桥呼叫辅助控制
Bridge to auxiliary control.
舰长，似乎好像有人在操纵这艘船
Captain, it seems as though someone else is running the ship.
塞夫林[通过对讲机]没错，有人正在操控这艘船
SEVRIN [OVER INTERCOM] That's right. Someone else is running the ship.
是我
I am.
所有功能，包括生命支持
All functions. Life support as well.
你无法干涉，因为我已经冻结了通往控制室的门
You cannot interfere, as I have frozen the doors to the control room.
在我们到达伊甸之前，我不打算将掌舵权交给你
I do not intend to hand over the helm to you until and unless we reach Eden.
如果我被阻止到达那个目的地
And if I am in any way prevented from reaching that destination,
我会摧毁这艘船和船上的所有人
I shall destroy this ship and all aboard.
他能这么做吗？
Can he do it?
他有这个能力，舰长
He has the capability, Captain.
[斯科特]他拦截了所有东西
[SCOTT] He's got everything channeled over.
开始对所有电路进行追溯
Start a trace-back on all circuits.
看看你是否能绕过他
See if you can bypass him.
你试试，我会回敬的
Do that, and I shall retaliate.
[塞夫林]我不会再警告你了
[SERVIN] I shall not warn you again.
舰长，我们正离开中立区
Captain, we're now leaving the neutral zone.
驶入罗慕伦空间
Bearing into Romulan space.
有巡逻队吗？
Any patrols?
没有
Negative.
很快就会有的
There will be soon.
塞夫林博士，你正在侵犯罗慕伦空间并危及星系和平
Dr. Sevrin, you are violating Romulan space and endangering the peace of the galaxy.
罗慕伦人会将此视为军事入侵并攻击
The Romulans will view this as a military intrusion and attack.
现在让飞船掉头
Bring the ship about now.
如果你让她掉头并返回星际基地，不会有任何指控
If you bring her about and return to Starbase, no charges will be leveled.
就像你说的，塞弗林兄弟
Like you said, Brother Sevrin.
否则，您将永远无法到达伊甸
If you do not, you will never reach Eden.
你和这艘船将被摧毁
You and this ship will be destroyed.
[亚当]他很忐忑，真的害怕了
[ADAM] He's got jelly in the belly. Real scared.
亚当，拉德，你被一个疯子领导
Adam, Rad, you are being led by a man who is insane.
你被他利用了
You are being used by him.
史波克，你告诉他们
Spock, you tell them.
亚当，我们的电脑库里有一份关于赛夫林博士的档案
Adam, there is a file on Dr. Sevrin in our computer banks.
里面是一份证明事实的报告
In it is a report attesting to the fact
他是一种被称为新合成球菌的芽孢杆菌菌株的携带者。
that he is a carrier of a bacillus strain known as Synthococcus novae.
真可怕啊！
Ain't that just awful?
你也会发现来自同一家医院的报告
You'll also find a report from the same hospital
提供他的完整的心理学档案
giving a full psychological profile on him
并投射了他的这些行为
and projecting these actions of his.
是的，兄弟
Yay, brother.
亚当，你知道我理解你
Adam, you know I reach you.
我相信你所寻求的
I believe in what you seek.
但是，你想要的和他想要的东西有着悲剧性的差异
But there is a tragic difference between what you want and what he wants.
你要把我弄哭了
You're making me cry.
在那里，他们建立了伊甸，塞夫林兄弟
There it is. They've established Eden, Brother Sevrin.
帕维尔说他们会的
Pavel said they would.
我们原来的航线一定是错误的
Our original course must have been in error.
我们什么时候到那里？
When will we get there?
以这个速度，三个小时
At this speed, three hours.
他们会试图说服我们立即改变路线，然后他们会进攻
They'll try to persuade us to change course presently and then they'll attack.
你打算怎么阻止他们？
How do you plan to stop them?
切断他们的生命支持系统？
By cutting off their life support?
我还有一个武器
I have another weapon.
你来控制，拉德兄弟
Take control, Brother Rad.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
对他们的电路进行调整
Making an adjustment on their circuits.
♪前往伊甸♪
♪ Heading out to Eden ♪
♪耶，兄弟♪
♪ Yay, brother ♪
♪前往伊甸♪
♪ Heading out to Eden ♪
♪我的身心不再有烦恼♪
♪ No more trouble in my body or my mind ♪
♪像国王一样生活，无论我找到什么♪
♪ Going to live like a king on whatever I find ♪
♪吃掉所有的水果并扔掉果皮♪
♪ Eat all the fruit and throw away the rind ♪
♪耶，兄弟♪
♪ Yay, brother ♪
♪耶♪
♪ Yay ♪
我们在伊甸的传感器范围内并继续接近
We are within sensor range of Eden and continuing to approach.
不管他们要做什么，他们现在要做
Whatever they're going to do, they're going to do now.
我们别无选择
We have no choice.
史波克先生，斯科特先生
Mr. Spock, Mr. Scott.
你什么时候用那个？
When will you use that?
在适当的时候
At the proper time.
当我们在轨道上时告诉我
Let me know when we're in orbit.
准时接近，就像他们绘制的那样，塞夫林兄弟
Approaching right on the dot, just as they plotted it, Brother Sevrin.
那会对他们有什么影响？
What will that do to them?
它是什么？
What is it?
我用声音对付他们
Well, I'm using sound against them.
频率超出超声波
Beyond the ultrasonic.
它会击晕他们，让我们有时间离开
It will stun them and allow us time to leave.
我们将乘坐他们的一架穿梭机
We'll go in one of their shuttlecraft.
那么高的音不会击晕
Sound pitch that high doesn't stun.
它能杀人
It destroys.
我记得当我们在文本中读到它时…
I remember when we read in the text that it...
我比那些文本更正确，伊琳娜
I've gone beyond those texts, Irina.
你的担心是正确的，但也请放心
It's correct for you to be concerned, but be assured also.
我们在伊甸上方的轨道上，塞夫林兄弟
We are in orbit over Eden, Brother Sevrin.
它确实能杀人
It does destroy.
我们不能让他们来追我们
We cannot allow them to come after us.
它不会触及我们这里，我可以控制这一切
It will not reach us in here. I can control it all.
我已经进行了调整，这样就会在片刻后暂停其效果
I have adjusted it so that it will suspend its effects after a few moments
让我们有时间逃离
and allow us time to escape.
然后在我们离开后，它会自动重新激活
Then after we've gone, it will automatically reactivate.
庆祝吧，兄弟们
Rejoice, brethren.
很快我们将一起踏入伊甸
Soon we shall step together into Eden.
[咝咝声]
[FIZZING]
[高音]
[HIGH-PITCHED TONE]
史波克
Spock.
没关系，史波克，它停止了
It's all right, Spock. It's stopped.
不，舰长，它没有停
No, Captain, it hasn't stopped.
已经超出了…
It's gone beyond...
舰长，他们正在使用…
Captain, they're using...
♪走进伊甸，耶，兄弟♪
♪ Stepping into Eden, yay, brother ♪
♪我的身心不再有烦恼♪
♪ No more trouble in my body or my mind ♪
♪像国王一样生活，无论我找到什么♪
♪ Gonna live like a king on whatever I find ♪
♪吃掉所有的水果并扔掉果皮♪
♪ Eat all the fruit and throw away the rind ♪
♪耶，兄弟♪
♪ Yay, brother ♪
现在我们可以离开了
Now we may leave.
舰长，去吧，你必须摧毁它
Captain, go. You must destroy it.
什么？
What is it?
超声波，面板
Ultrasonics. The panel.
柯克呼叫轮机部
Kirk to engineering.
舰桥？
Bridge?
机库甲板？
Hangar deck?
柯克呼叫传送室
Kirk to transporter room.
柯克呼叫舰桥
Kirk to bridge.
你能听到我吗？请回答
Do you read me? Come in.
我是苏鲁，舰长，我们怎么了？
Sulu here, Captain. What happened to us?
我听到了一声哨声，然后…
I heard a whistle and then...
先别管，我们能控制这艘船吗？
Never mind. Do we have control of the ship?
[契科夫]不，长官，处于辅助控制状态
[CHEKOV] No, sir. Control is in auxiliary.
如有必要 我们能脱离轨道吗？
Can we break out of orbit if we have to?
[苏鲁]我想可以，长官
[SULU] I think so, sir.
[男]机库甲板呼叫舰长
[MAN] Hangar deck to Captain.
我是柯克
Kirk here.
长官，有一艘穿梭机被带走了
Sir, one of the shuttlecrafts has been taken.
我们都被打晕了
We were all knocked out.
待命
Stand by.
你有任何罗慕伦人的读数吗？
Do you read any Romulans?
没有，舰长
Negative, Captain.
但是，我正在收集穿梭机的读数
However, I am picking up the shuttlecraft.
在哪里？
Where?
它已经着陆了
It has landed.
除了那些在穿梭机上的人，我完全读不到生命体，人形或动物都没有
Except for those on the craft, I read no life at all, either humanoid or animal.
辅助控制呼叫麦考伊医生
Auxiliary control to Dr. McCoy.
老骨头，你没事吧？
Bones, are you all right?
[麦考伊]是的，吉姆
[MCCOY] Yes, Jim.
传送室，待命
Stand by, transporter room.
准备全套医疗装备
Full medical gear.
[契科夫]舰桥呼叫柯克舰长
[CHEKOV] Bridge to Captain Kirk.
您想打开通讯器吗，长官？
Do you wish to open communications, sir?
不
No.
不，他们试图摧毁我们，让他们认为他们成功了
No, they tried to destroy us. Let them think they succeeded.
我希望坐标归零，这样我们传送下去的时候，就不会被他们看到
I want the coordinates zeroed in so that when we beam down, we won't be visible to them.
斯科提，你来掌舵
Scotty, you have the conn.
如果罗慕伦人出现，试着让他们理解
If Romulans appear, try to make them understand.
我不想挑起战斗
I do not want to provoke combat.
史波克先生，契科夫先生，去传送室和我们汇合
Mr. Spock. Mr. Chekov, join us in the transporter room.
传说是真的，舰长
The legends were true, Captain.
一个极其美丽的星球
A fantastically beautiful planet.
伊甸
Eden.
这就是他们相信他们会发现的吗？
Is this what they believed they'd find?
那我就明白了
Then I can understand.
散开，小心地靠近
Spread out. Approach with caution.
塞夫林博士…
Dr. Sevrin...
[大喊]
[SHOUTS]
怎么了？
What is it?
花，长官，我摸了摸，它就像火一样
The flower, sir. I touched it. It's like fire.
是烧伤
It's burned.
所有这些植物体都充满了酸
All this plant life is full of acid.
即使是草，吉姆
Even the grass, Jim.
我们的衣服会保护我们吗？
Will our clothing protect us?
应该能撑一会儿
It should for a while.
[史波克]舰长
[SPOCK] Captain.
老骨头？
Bones?
有毒，果实是致命的
Poison. The fruit is deadly.
他的名字是亚当
His name was Adam.
穿梭机在那儿
There's the shuttlecraft.
来，我们会帮助你
Here. We'll help you.
塞夫林博士，老骨头
Dr. Sevrin. Bones.
他应该被传送到船上，吉姆
He should be beamed aboard, Jim.
在这里我无法完全帮助他
He needs more than I can do for him here.
史波克呼叫企业号
Spock to Enterprise.
[斯科特]这里是企业号
[Scott] Enterprise here.
准备把伤员传送上船
Stand by to beam aboard injured party.
医疗队到传送室报道
Medical team to the transporter room.
不，我们不会离开
No, we're not leaving.
我们可以帮助你登船
We can help you aboard the ship.
我们不会离开伊甸，我们都不会
We're not leaving Eden, none of us.
理智点，博士
Be sensible, Doctor.
我们不走
We're not leaving.
[麦考伊]回来，你个蠢货
[McCoy] Come back here, you fool!
塞夫林，不要！你会害死自己！
Sevrin, don't! You'll kill yourself!
不要吃那个
Don't bite into that.
[柯克]别！
[KIRK] Stop !
它多么美丽啊
It was so beautiful.
我联系上星际基地了，舰长
I have Starbase now, Captain.
提醒他们我们有那四个人
Alert them that we have the four,
我们已准备好把他们传送下来
and we're ready to beam them down.
并标记事件结束
And mark the incident closed.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
舰桥呼叫传送室，斯科提，他们在吗？
Bridge to Transporter. Scotty, are they there?
有三个，长官，还有一个随时可能到
Three of them, sir. Expecting a fourth any minute.
待命
Stand by.
契科夫先生，你想参加吗？
Mr. Chekov, do you wish to attend?
舰长，我想先为我这段时间的行为道歉
Captain, I wish first to apologize for my conduct during this time.
我没有完全遵守纪律
I did not maintain myself under proper discipline.
我的行为危及了这艘船及其人员
I endangered the ship and its personnel by my conduct.
我恭敬地接受纪律处分
I respectfully submit myself for disciplinary action.
谢谢，契科夫先生
Thank you, Mr. Chekov.
你做了你必须做的
You did what you had to do.
就像我们所有人一样
As did we all.
甚至你的朋友也是
Even your friends.
你可以走了
You may go.
谢谢，长官
Thank you, sir.
我是来告别的
I was coming to say goodbye.
我也是来和你说再见的
And I was coming to say goodbye to you.
要不正确一点…偶尔
Be incorrect... occasionally.
而你要正确一点
And you be correct.
偶尔
Occasionally.
加柳林小姐
Miss Galliulin.
我真诚地希望你不要放弃对伊甸的寻找
It is my sincere wish that you do not give up your search for Eden.
我毫不怀疑你会找到它
I have no doubt but that you will find it.
或自己创造它
Or make it yourselves.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们…明白了，史波克先生
We... reach, Mr. Spock.